Curriculum Vitae Tupokigwe Isagah

PERSONAL INFORMATION



SUMMARY

Tupokigwe Isagah

💎 Auf dem Hellen Weyer 1-314, 56072 Koblenz

+49 15778428719

https://isagah.github.io/

Gender Female | Date of birth 10/08/1986 | Nationality: Tanzanian

A research analyst enthusiast about solving complex problems using analytical skills. Highly interested in working with teams to optimize the process of planning and designing IT capabilities to meet the objectives of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2015- Present

University of Koblenz-Landau – IWVI Research Group- Germany

Research Assistant

- Analysed technology and business challenges and provide innovative solutions in public sector
- Performed design and system analysis, requirement analysis and stakeholder management of mobile government services
- Translate user and designer requirements into design specification
- Construct a comprehensive method for planning and designing mobile public services
- Establish a metamodel of mobile government service design
- Provide principles and guidelines for delivering innovative public services via mobile devices
- Provide an analysis of enterprise architecture and agile methods application in designing government services
- Published four scientific papers

07/2010 - 11/2015

Mzumbe University- Department of Computing Science Studies- Tanzania

Assistant Lecturer

- Seminar review and supervise students in practical training
- Project member in MU-VLIRUOS projects (zone IT): Developed the proposal (Zone IT) and performed requirement analysis of the desired solution

03/2010 - 06/2010

Tanzania Atomic Energy, Arusha - Tanzania

Nuclear Instrumentation Research Assistant

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2015 - 12/2018

Ph.D. in Information System Management

University of Koblenz-Landau

Title: Framework for Designing M-government Services

2011 -- 2013

MSc. in Information System

University of Osmania

2005 -- 2008

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communication

University of Dar es Salaam

2018

Coursera

Data-Driven Decision Making- Course by PwC

PERSONAL SKILLS

Curriculum Vitae Tupokigwe Isagah

Languages

Swahili - Mother Tongue

English – Fluent

German - Intermediate

Computer Skills

- Microsoft Office Tools (Word, Excel, Visio, and PowerPoint)
- Data analysis (SPSS, MAXQDA and (Python-Intermediate user))
- Programming languages (Java & C++ Basic user) ,(PHP-Intermediate user)
- Academic writing tools like Jabref, Citavi, and Zotero
- SQL (intermediate level)
- Good command of online survey tools like LimeSurvey and SurveyMonkey

Job-related skills

Good command of :

- The Open Group Enterprise Architecture (TOGAF)
- Information systems analysis, design and evaluation approaches
- Quantitative, Qualitative and Design Science methodology
- User-centered design principles
- Data sharing standards
- Requirement analysis and management approaches
- Stakeholder management techniques
- Business Process Model (BPM) tools and techniques
- Software design and analysis, enterprise application development, UML, and waterfall method
- Intermediate command of:
 - Agile methodologies
 - European Interoperability Framework (EIF)
 - Mobile technologies

Communication skills

- ■Teamwork
 - Work cooperatively with others toward accomplishment of a shared goal Blend perfectly in International groups
- Excellent presentation, written and verbal communication skills
- Ability to communicate complex ideas in simple language
- Good experience in writing and presenting minutes of the meeting

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Publications

- Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2018, May. Framework for designing m-government, services in developing countries. In Proceedings of the 19th Annual International Conference on Digital Government Research: Governance in the Data Age. Page(s) 44. ACM
- ■Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2018, April. Addressing Requirements of M-Government Services: Empirical Study from Designers' Perspectives. In Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Governance. Page(s) 599 608. ACM
- Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2017, March. Mobile Government Applications: Challenges and Needs for a Comprehensive Design Approach. In Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Governance. Page(s) 423 432
- Bunar, C. and Isagah, T., 2016. Assessing mobile participation: A case study of iCitizen, buycott, and Ushahidi. Electronic Government and Electronic Participation. Page(s) 599 608.